Brian Lam

brian-lam.netlify.app | San Jose, California | (408) 981-8982 | Lamb9@uci.edu

INTRODUCTION

Front-end developer specializing in React with a strong knowledge of JavaScript and web standards such as HTML and CSS. Able to grasp concepts quickly and adapt to new frameworks or technologies. Has experience working in a team environment, communicating effectively, and meeting deadlines having worked in the accounting industry.

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine

Jun 2020

B.A. in Business Economics

Dean's Honor list: Winter 2017, Fall 2017, Spring 2018, Winter 2020, Spring 2020

PROJECTS

MyAnimeFaves | React | Single Page Application

- Developed a SPA using React that fetches anime data from an API using a query specified by the user
- Utilized Redux to manage app-wide state while using action creator thunks to handle side effects
- Handled URL changes using React-Router to render new content on the screen within a split second
- Integrated Firebase authentication to securely log users in and store user data into a Firebase database

To-Do List | React | Web Application

- Deployed a web application using React that allows users to create, read, update, and delete tasks
- Managed state using react hooks and implemented cross-component state using prop chains
- Implemented task filtering by date using JavaScript array methods and the Date constructor
- Persisted user data by utilizing local storage to store user data onto the browser

Hungrify | HTML, CSS, JS| Single Page Application

- Engineered a front-end application using vanilla HTML, CSS, and JS while following a MVC architecture
- Utilized event listeners to render content conditionally based on hash changes
- Maintained a publisher-subscriber pattern by handling events inside the controller and listening for them in the view
- Implemented a bookmarking feature by storing user data in the browser with local storage

WORK EXPERIENCE

Novogradac & Company LLP | Staff Accountant Intern - San Francisco, CA

Jan 2021 – Apr 2021

- Completed comprehensive audits and reviews based on PCAOB standards and cooperated with 5+ financial
 institutions daily to confirm client account balances resulting in timely submitted audits
- Succeeded in preparing and filing tax returns within the company's allocated budget time of 8 hours per return while working in a fast-paced environment due to the tax season

Rocket EMS | **Receiving Clerk** – Santa Clara, CA

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

- Inspected 100+ packages per day verifying goods against invoices and reconciling inconsistencies, ensuring a smooth transition from received goods to work orders
- Applied attention to detail when processing and updating records for incoming shipments while simultaneously
 communicating with buyers and project managers, allowing the company to meet urgent customer demands

Joon Shabu Shabu | Server – Tustin, CA

Oct 2019 - Sep 2020

- Maintained a steady workflow by quickly serving food and drinks to 50+ customers daily while meeting customer needs, resulting in tips of \$500+ per day
- Memorized store menu and ingredients of 50+ items to clarify any customer queries or health concerns, resulting in quality customer service and 5 star reviews on yelp

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, Bootstrap

Hobbies/Interest: Computer Games, Board Games, Biking, Anime, The Office